https://www.canadiannorth.com/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Privacy Policy
General StatementCanadian North respects your right to privacy and is dedicated to the protection of your personal information. Canadian North follows the requirements Canada’s Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA) when we collect, use or disclose your personal information.AccountabilityCanadian North has appointed a Privacy Officer who is responsible for ensuring compliance with PIPEDA and this policy. Should you have any questions regarding this policy or concerns with Canadian North’s compliance with the requirements of PIPEDA, you may contact Canadian North’s Privacy Officer.This policy applies to anyone who collects, uses and discloses personal information on behalf of Canadian North, including employees and third party service providers.Canadian North’s Customer Privacy Policy may change from time to time, however changes will not impact Canadian North’s commitment to the safeguarding of your personal information, or the manner in which we use it. Any such change will be posted on this website. Canadian North reserves the right to modify this policy at any time, so please review it frequently.PurposeCanadian North collects personal information for the following reasons:When you Book a FlightWhen you book a flight with Canadian North you will be required to provide certain personal information to complete your transaction. This may include your name, address, telephone number, credit card number and expiry date. This information is required for identification purposes, for contact purposes, and to complete the process of your purchase.Requirements of Government AuthoritiesThere may be situations where Canadian North is required by law to collect, use or disclose personal information about you without your knowledge or consent. These situations are most likely to arise when you are traveling with us and a government authority has requested the release of certain information. Canadian North may be required to disclose to customs and immigration authorities (of any country) information that we hold about you and your travel arrangements.Special AssistanceCanadian North offers a range of services to passengers with special needs and for unaccompanied minors.In order to properly serve persons with special needs and to ensure the health and safety of all concerned, Canadian North may require additional personal information, including relevant medical information, dietary requests and information on particular requirements, such as whether a wheelchair, oxygen supply or other special equipment are required. This information may be disclosed to allow Canadian North the ability to properly provide special assistance.In order to serve unaccompanied minors, Canadian North will require personal information concerning the following people: the child, the parents (or guardians), the adults dropping off the child, the adults supervising the child at any stopovers and the adults meeting the child at the end of their travel.DiscountsCanadian North offers special discounts for seniors, Elders, children and bereavement fares. To assess fare eligibility and ensure that your ticket is correctly processed Canadian North may require you to provide personal information such as your date of birth or a certificate of death.Visiting our WebsiteSome of Canadian North’s web pages may contain “cookies,” which are data that may be sent to your Web browser and stored on your computer. This allows our computer server to recognize you when you visit our website in the future and also allows Canadian North to develop our website to meet the needs of our users. These cookies do not usually contain personally identifying information.First in Line Mailing ListsCustomers are able to register to become a member of First in Line on an optional basis. By registering, customers provide Canadian North with their personal information to allow Canadian North to inform them of seat sales and other promotional offers. Upon your request, you can remove your information at any time by sending an email to reservat@canadiannorth.com.Your personal information is not provided to other companies and you will only receive information from Canadian North.Employment OpportunitiesCanadian North advertises position vacancies on its website. If an individual applies for a job they can either complete an application form that asks for personal information or they can submit their resume. This information is used to contact you and to review your application. Your application will remain on file for six months, after which it is destroyed. Canadian North’s Customer Privacy Policy may change from time to time, however changes will not impact Canadian North’s commitment to the safeguarding of your personal information, or the manner in which we use it. Any such change will be posted on this website. Canadian North reserves the right to modify this policy at any time, so please review it frequently.ConsentWhen you book your travel with Canadian North, the fact that you are doing so provides Canadian North with your implied consent to use your information to fulfill your request.If you register with Canadian North’s First in Line service, submit your application for a job within Canadian North, or participate in a promotional contest, you are consenting to allow Canadian North to contact you.Limiting CollectionCanadian North will limit the collection of personal information to that which is necessary for the purposes that have been identified. Such information will be collected by fair and lawful means.The amount and type of information collected will be limited to that which is necessary to fulfill the purposes identified.Limiting Use, Disclosure and RetentionCanadian North will not use or disclose your personal information for any purpose other than those for which it was collected without your express consent, or as required or permitted by law.Information will be retained only as long as necessary to fulfil the purpose for which it was collected.SafeguardsCanadian North’s Internet systems are configured with data encryption. This means that that when an individual sends personal information to Canadian North, such as a credit card number, the electronic data is protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to ensure safe transmission.In addition, any personal information that is kept in hard copy is retained in secure facilities. Access to these facilities is restricted to those who need it in order to deliver services.OpennessCanadian North’s privacy practices are as outlined in this policy. Should you have any questions or comments you may contact our Privacy Officer at privacyofficer@canadiannorth.com.Canadian North will make readily available specific information about its policies and practices relating to the management of personal information to individuals who request it.Individual AccessUpon request, an individual will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of their personal information and will be given access to that information subject to the exclusions set out in the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act. An individual will be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate.Challenging ComplianceAn individual can address a challenge concerning Canadian North’s compliance with the above policy to the Director, Employee and Labour Relations, Canadian North’s Privacy Officer.Canadian North will investigate all complaints. If it concludes that a complaint is justified Canadian North will take appropriate measures, including, if necessary, amending its policies and procedures.The Privacy Officer can be contacted through email at privacyofficer@canadiannorth.com, or in writing to:Privacy OfficerCanadian North20 Cope DriveKanata, ONK2M 2V8If the Privacy Officer is unable to resolve your concern, additional information can be obtained from the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at www.privcom.gc.ca.
